Ben Klein UX Designer

User Experience Designer with a background in animation and storyboarding. Expert storyteller experienced in analyzing a problem from various angles to come up with an array of creative solutions quickly and presenting them in an aesthetic way, while keeping the client's and user's needs and goals at the centre of the creative process.

UX/UI Projects

Nonna | UX/UI designer | Inclusive Cooking App

Cambridge | June 2021- November 2021

 Applied a user-centered design process to design a inclusive cooking app starting with user research and ending with an interactive, high-fidelity prototype

Relevant Work Experience

Art & Design Teacher | Lycée de Garçons

Luxembourg | August 2020- July 2021

- Boosted students' and faculty's work flow by 50% by teaching them on how to use a wide range of digital editing and drawing softwares
- Spearheaded and organized a design program for students and faculty by effectively mediating between and bringing together different departments
- Guided, motivated and critiqued students during homework assignments and collaborative projects pushing them to create some of that year's best work

Storyboard artist | PTD

Luxembourg | March 2020 - Mai 2020

- Created dynamic storyboards and polished animatics during pre-production which saved the team significant time and money later in production
- Collaborated closely and met daily with the director in order to make her vision come to life while staying within a tight budget
- Resolved story, shot, and coherence issues to more efficiently translate the script into pleasing visuals

Storyboard artist | CG LUX

Luxembourg | October 2019 - February 2020

- Assisted and motivated the director and fellow storyboard artists to translate the script into a coherent vision
- Maximized the re-use of 2D backgrounds by 30% helping the 3D modelers stay within budget and on time
- Composed model sheets in my free time to speed up pre-production and to save the team money and time

Contract storyboard artist | SONY Playstation

San Francisco | 2016-2018

- Worked on several commercials for different Playstation platforms ranging from PS4, to PS Pro over to Playstation VR for their presence at E3 helping them win several big contracts
- Collaborated closely with producer and art director in order to bring their exact vision to life under very tight deadlines

Contact Info

kleinben.myportfolio.com thebenklein@gmail.com +352 661 402 461 LinkedIn: https://www. linkedin.com/in/benklein-83066945/

Soft Skills

Empathy
Active listening
Creative Problem-solving
Quick ideation skills

UX/UI Skills

Primary Research
Secondary Research
User Personas
User Journeys
Usability Analysis
Storyboarding
Creating Sitemaps
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Testing
UI Design
Style Guides
Sitemaps

Tools

Photoshop Illustrator Adobe XD

Education

UX Design CertificateCareerFoundry
Berlin
2021

Bachelor in 2D Animation

Academy of Art University San Francisco 2014